# Nicolás Eduardo Mato

# Linux System Administrator

**Website:** <u>nicolasmato.com.ar</u> **Mail:** matonicolas[at]gmail[dot]com

## **Skills & Knowledge Areas**

Critical thinking, decision-making, and problem-solving.

Specialized skills and experience in companies ranging from small to large businesses.

Managing Linux systems in production environments since 2006.

Using Git and its major platforms since 2015.

Backend infrastructure as code implementation.

Experience leading teams of up to 10 people in a business environment.

Advocate for best practices across the organization.

- GNU/Linux System Administrator.
- Ethical Hacking Expert.
- Virtual Machines Environment.
- Containers & Cloud Computing.
- Bash Scripting. Backend Developer.

## **Professional Experience**

Galicia Mas - SRE Linux Engineer | Dec 2024 - Present

RHEL Infrastructure Administration & Monitoring. Red Hat Satellite. Red Hat Fuse. Red Hat 3scale API Management. VMWare Administration. Infrastructure Monitoring Implementation: AppDynamics, Crowdstrike, BHOM. Bash Scripting, Control-M & Rundeck Automation. ESXi. Cisco UCS. Configuration Baseline Management Vulnerabilities - Remediation & Patching. Cloud & Repository: Jenkins, Ansible, Git, AWS, Nessus.

HSBC Argentina - SRE Linux Engineer | Feb 2022 - Dec 2024

RHEL Infrastructure Administration & Monitoring VMWare Administration. Virtualbox. Proxmox. ESXi. Cisco UCS. Infrastructure Monitoring Implementation: AppDynamics, Puppet. Bash Scripting, Control-M & Rundeck Automation. Configuration Baseline Management Vulnerabilities - Remediation & Patching. Cloud & Repository: Jenkins, Ansible, Git, AWS, Nessus.

Ministerio del Interior - SR Linux Sysadmin | May 2019 - Feb 2022

Linux & Windows Server Administration. VMWare & Oracle Virtualbox Administrator. Infrastructure Monitoring: Check MK, Nagios, Grafana, Zabbix, Openshift. Websites Maintenance for Ministerio del Interior. MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB. Jenkins, Gitlab, Docker, Kubernetes. SSL Certificates. Migration and Upgrade of Red Hat and Debian Infrastructure. ESET Protect Antivirus Implementation & Management.

Levi's Arg - SR Support | SR Server Admin | Network Security | Apr 2011 - Apr 2019

Technical Support. Windows & Linux Sysadmin.
VMWare & Oracle Virtualbox Administrator. Cisco & Microtik Router.
ERP Implementation [Worknet]. Sell Point Retail Implementation.
Mail Server & FS Management. LDAP, Active Directory.
Firewall Implementation. Watchguard, GFI Mailessentials.
McAfee ePO Implementation & Admin.

PSA Peugeot Citroën - SR Technical Support | May 2006 - Apr 2011

Technical Support. VMWare Administration. Windows & Linux Administration [Suse, Debian/Ubuntu]. Full support on Factory Network & Printers Infrastructure. SDI system, V3NET Management.

#### Edenor S.A. - Technical Support | Feb 2004 - Apr 2006

Technical Support.
Microsoft Windows NT4, 2000, XP.
VMWare Management. Novell, Zenworks, Groupwise.
MySap 7.10, Ryca, Gestproy, Eyretel Eware, Nexus, GS Online.

SANDVIK Coromant - Technical Support | Jan 2001 - Feb 2004

Technical Support. PC Maintenance Hardware and Software Management. VMWare Management. Windows Server & Linux Admin.

Camara de Comercio de 3 de Febrero - Technology Professor | Jul 1999 - Dec 2001

Microsoft Windows & Office Teacher. PC Assembly & Maintenance, hardware and software management.

## Languages

- Spanish [Native]
- English [B1 Fluent]

#### **Formation**

### E.E.T.N° 1 "Manuel Belgrano"

Technician in Electronics and automation of PLC (Program Logic Controller).

#### **Educación IT**

- Backend Web Developer, HTML, Javascript, PHP, CSS.

### **CLA Linux Institute**

- Linux System Administrator
- Ethical Hacking Expert
- Proxmox Virtual Environment
- Bacula Postfix
- Cloud Computing

## **Red Hat Enterprise Linux**

- RHEL Certified System Administration [RHCSA]
- RHEL Certified Engineer [RHCE] D0180/D0280: Openshift Admin I & II
- RHEL Certified Specialist in Managing Automation with Ansible Automation Platform.

#### **Hobbies**

- Playing drums and bass.
- Cooking and exploring gastronomy.
- Reading (I own a library with +300 books).